<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. All rights reserved -->

<!--   
			SUMMARY  - 
A list of all main events to be called by lists
	does not include sub-events)
	

Structure:
	NO_FUEL_FLEET
	
No Beacon:    	NO_FUEL (this is a list)
	FUEL_FLEET_DELAY
	FUEL_NOTHING
	FUEL_TRADER
	FUEL_EXPLORE
	FUEL_APPROACH
	
Beacon:    NO_FUEL_DISTRESS (this is a list)
	FUEL_FLEET_DISTRESS
	FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS
	FUEL_SELLER_DISTRESS
	FUEL_TRADER_DISTRESS

Sector Specific:
	
--->








<!-- NO FUEL stuff -->

<event name="NO_FUEL_FLEET">
	<text>The Rebel fleet has caught up to you. You detect significant fuel reserves in one of their closer fighters and move in to attack.  Maybe you can still pull this off.</text>
	<ship load = "REBEL_FLEET_FUEL" hostile ="true"/>
	<fleet>rebel</fleet>
</event>
	
	
	
	
	





<!-------------------
DEFAULT FUEL EVENTS
Beacon Off.....
-------------------->
<eventList name="NO_FUEL">
	<event load="FUEL_FLEET_DELAY"/>
	
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING"/>
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING"/>
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING"/>
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING"/>
	
	<event load="FUEL_TRADER"/>
	<event load="FUEL_EXPLORE"/>
	<event load="FUEL_APPROACH"/>
	<event load="FUEL_OFF_ENGI_DUBIOUS"/>
	<event load="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_WRECK"/>
</eventList>

<event name="FUEL_FLEET_DELAY">
	<text load="FUEL_FLEET_DELAY_LIST"/>		
	<modifyPursuit amount="-1"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event load="NO_FUEL"/>
	</choice>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_FLEET_DELAY_LIST">
	<text>As you are keeping a low profile, you're certain that the Rebel fleet is having a hard time tracking your ship.</text>
	<text>Since your distress beacon has not been activated, you feel confident that the Rebel fleet is having difficulty tracking you.  It should buy you a little time.</text>
	<text>Long range scanners indicate the Rebel fleet has temporarily paused its advance on your position. Your decision to leave the distress beacon deactivated was farsighted.</text>
	<text>Scanners show that the Rebel fleet has ceased its pursuit for a short time.</text>
	<text>Your intuition as captain is telling you that the Rebels are having a hard time trying to find your ship.</text>
	<text>Without a distress beacon or any FTL signatures to trace, you're sure that the Rebels are struggling to find you.  You can only hope their confusion lasts until more fuel can be found.</text>
	<text>The Rebel fleet seems to be unable to locate your ship's signature.  If only you could get some fuel, you might still have a chance to place some distance between you and them...</text>
</textList>

<event name="FUEL_NOTHING">
	<text load="FUEL_NOTHING_LIST"/>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_NOTHING_LIST">
	<text>No ship is in scanning range and no one arrives at the beacon.</text>
	<text>Your waiting yields nothing while the fleet surely gets closer...</text>
	<text>A freighter suddenly arrives nearby. They are so close you can almost wave at them, but your hails are ignored and the ship quickly jumps away.</text>
	<text>Small traffic passes within a short distance of you, but no one responds to your hails.</text>
	<text>The only ship within hailing range appears to be a civilian vessel. However, it quickly leaves once it picks up your signal.</text>
	<text>As you wait, a small asteroid storm pelts softly against your shields and hull.</text>
	<text>You begin to wonder if turning on the beacon would be worth the risk of detection.  The fleet slowly approaches.</text>
	<text>You contemplate the vastness of space.</text>
	<text>The prolonged wait in empty space is causing tension among the crew. Still no contact.</text>
	<text>Cabin fever begins to spread among your crew.</text>
	<text>Long range scanners detect a small settlement, but they refuse all contact.</text>
</textList>

<event name="FUEL_TRADER">   <!-- this continues in the DISTRESS section -->
	<text load="FUEL_TRADER_TEXT_LIST"/>
	<ship load="CIVILIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
	<choice>
		<text>Gladly trade.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_TRADER_HIGH_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Respectfully decline.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_TRADER_PT2"/>
	</choice>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_TRADER_TEXT_LIST">
	<text>A merchant ship jumps into the sector and you quickly hail them asking for help.  They respond, "Perhaps we could work out an exchange..."</text>
	<text>A number of ships pass through the sector.  You relay your message to each, and one finally responds.  "I can't help much right now but perhaps we can trade."</text>
	<text>A nearby settlement sends a small ship in your direction.  It keeps its distance and hails you, "We can give you fuel for a price.  Just don't even think of doing anything rash.  We've got a teleporter at our base and a squad ready to defend us.</text>
	<text>A large caravan of merchant ships jumps to a location near your position.  Sensing an opportunity, one ship breaks off from the fleet to offer you an exchange.</text>
	<text>A modified YT-1300 freighter jumps to an area near your sector.  Your gut tells you these people are smugglers, but they seem to be feeling altruistic and present an offer of assistance.</text>
</textList>
	
<event name="FUEL_EXPLORE">
	<text>Although your lack of fuel cells prevents your ship from jumping, you can still use your impulse engines.  Will you spend some time exploring the nearby system?</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Explore the nearby area.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_EXPLORE_LIST"/>  
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Stay near the beacon.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="FUEL_EXPLORE_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>You happen across a small asteroid field near the beacon.</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Approach the asteroid field to scan it.</text>
			<event load="ASTEROID_EXPLORE_RESULTS"/>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Avoid the risk.</text>
			<event/>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You find a small outpost for local travelers, but it seems few ships in this area employ FTL drives. Their stock of fuel cells is small and their price high, but beggars can't be choosers...</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Trade 20 scrap for 5 fuel.</text>
			<event>
				<text>You gladly make the trade.</text>
				<item_modify>
					<item type="fuel" min="5" max="5"/>
					<item type="scrap" min="-20" max="-20"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Trade 10 scrap for 2 fuel.</text>
			<event>
				<text>This fuel won't last long, but you gladly make the trade.</text>
				<item_modify>
					<item type="fuel" min="2" max="2"/>
					<item type="scrap" min="-10" max="-10"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Trade 5 scrap for 1 fuel.</text>
			<event>
				<text>This fuel won't last long, but at least you can jump to another beacon.</text>
				<item_modify>
					<item type="fuel" min="1" max="1"/>
					<item type="scrap" min="-5" max="-5"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Don't make a trade.</text>
			<event/>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>No ships respond to your hails and you find nothing of interest.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You wander within scanning range of a small Rebel automated scout!</text>
		<ship load="REBEL_AUTO_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
</eventList>
	
<event name="FUEL_APPROACH">
	<text>A ship approaches.  They hail you saying, "You need some fuel?  We'll prepare to dock to help."</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Graciously accept their offer.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_APPROACH_ACCEPT_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Request that they keep their distance</text>
		<event load="FUEL_APPROACH_DECLINE_LIST"/>
	</choice>  
	<choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="3">
		<text>(Advanced Sensors) Run a detailed scan with your sensors before responding.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_APPROACH_SCAN_LIST"/>
	</choice>    
	<choice hidden="true" req="ADV_SCANNERS">
		<text>(Long-Ranged Scanners) Run a detailed scan before responding.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_APPROACH_SCAN_LIST"/>
	</choice>    
</event>
<eventList name="FUEL_APPROACH_ACCEPT_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>They pull close to your ship and unload some fuel saying, "Try not to run out of fuel again.  These are dangerous times; who knows who could have showed up."</text>
		<ship load="CIVILIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="2" max="6"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>   <!-- this continues in the DISTRESS section -->
		<text>They approach and dock with your ship.  On board they present an offer.</text>
		<ship load="CIVILIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
		<choice>
			<text>Gladly trade.</text>
			<event load="FUEL_TRADER_HIGH_LIST"/>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Respectfully decline.</text>
			<event load="FUEL_TRADER_PT2"/>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>As their ship pulls up next to yours, their captain continues, "Yes, we'll certainly help...  Help to relieve you of that nice ship!"  Sensors detect a hidden teleporter has been activated.  We've been boarded!</text>
		<ship load="PIRATE_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
		<boarders min="2" max="3" class="human"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>As they approach, you detect their weapons powering up.  It seems their intentions are hostile!</text>
		<ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="FUEL_APPROACH_DECLINE_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>"I assure you that we mean no harm.  See, we'll send some fuel over on a transport."  A small ship docks and offloads some fuel just as they said.  They leave, saying, "Stay cautious, friend."</text>
		<ship load="CIVILIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="1" max="4"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>"No one trusts anyone these days..."  The ship jumps away.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>They reply,"Keep our distance?  Let's see if you can stop us!"  They power up their weapons and advance.</text>
		<ship load="PIRATE_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="FUEL_APPROACH_SCAN_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>Sensors indicate their ship is without military-grade weaponry, even small arms.  You allow them to dock and they give you some fuel saying, "I remember a time when we didn't have to be so paranoid about each others intentions... Stay safe."</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="3" max="7"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Sensors are picking up armed crew and considerably more weaponry than is legal for a craft of this size.  This is surely a trap.</text>
		<choice>
			<text>Power up weapons and prepare for a fight.</text>
			<event>
				<ship load="PIRATE_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice req="cloaking" hidden="true"> 
			<text>(Cloaking) Cloak and get out of scanning range before they have a chance to lock on.</text>
			<event>
				<text>Your highly advanced cloaking system allows you to get out of range easily since they were still out of firing range.  Eventually the ship jumps away.</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>		
</eventList>

	
	

	
	
	
	
	
<!-------------------
DEFAULT FUEL EVENTS
Beacon On!!!!
-------------------->


<eventList name="NO_FUEL_DISTRESS">
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS"/>
	<event load="FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS"/>
	
	<event load="FUEL_SELLER_DISTRESS"/>
	<event load="FUEL_TRADER_DISTRESS"/>
	<event load="FUEL_EXPLORE"/>
	<event load="FUEL_APPROACH"/>
	<event load="FUEL_ON_SLUG_OVERPRICED"/>
	<event load="FUEL_ON_SLUG_CHUCKLE"/>
	<event load="FUEL_ON_MANTIS_ATTACK"/>
	<event load="FUEL_ON_REBEL_WARNING"/>
	<event load="FUEL_ON_REBEL_ATTACK"/>
</eventList>






<event name="FUEL_FLEET_DISTRESS">
	<text load="FUEL_FLEET_DISTRESS_LIST"/>		
	<modifyPursuit amount="1"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event load="NO_FUEL"/>
	</choice>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_FLEET_DISTRESS_LIST">
	<text>As you are keeping a low profile, you're certain that the Rebel fleet is having a hard time tracking your ship.</text>
	<text>Since your distress beacon has not been activated, you feel confident that the Rebel fleet is having difficulty tracking you.  It should buy you a little time.</text>
	<text>Long range scanners indicate the Rebel fleet has temporarily paused its advance on your position. Your decision to leave the distress beacon deactivated was farsighted.</text>
	<text>Scanners show that the Rebel fleet has ceased its pursuit for a short time.</text>
	<text>Your intuition as captain is telling you that the Rebels are having a hard time trying to find your ship.</text>
	<text>Without a distress beacon or any FTL signatures to trace, you're sure that the Rebels are struggling to find you.  You can only hope their confusion lasts until more fuel can be found.</text>
	<text>The Rebel fleet seems to be unable to locate your ship's signature.  If only you could get some fuel, you might still have a chance to place some distance between you and the Rebels...</text>
</textList>

<event name="FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS">
	<text load="FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS_LIST"/>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_NOTHING_DISTRESS_LIST">
	<text>You contemplate that it is fortunate the ship's life support system does not rely on FTL fuel cells.</text>
	<text>Nothing happens.  Your calls go unanswered.</text>
	<text>The distress beacon's light is the only movement visible outside the ship.</text>
	<text>No ships jump into the sector...</text>
	<text>A few passing ships seem oblivious to your distress call and ignore all hails.</text>
	<text>A few civilian ships are within scanning range, yet none respond to your calls.</text>
	<text>No ships pass through the area.</text>
</textList>
	
<event name="FUEL_SELLER_DISTRESS">
	<ship load="AUTO_FUEL_SELLER" hostile="false"/>  
	<text>A small ship arrives with a message, "This automated ship will provide re-fueling services once a monetary exchange is complete.  Complimentary amounts of fuel are available in emergencies only."</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Request emergency fuel reserves.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"This ship has registered that your one-time complimentary emergency fuel allowance has been consumed."</text>
			<autoReward level="LOW">fuel_only</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>5 Fuel for 20 Scrap.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Automated re-fueling complete."</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="fuel" min="5" max="5"/>
				<item type="scrap" min="-20" max="-20"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Buy 2 Fuel for 8 Scrap.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Automated re-fueling complete."</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="fuel" min="2" max="2"/>
				<item type="scrap" min="-8" max="-8"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Attack the automated ship.</text>
		<event>
			<ship hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>




<!-- This number of events offers the players a bad trade, then if they say no, a chance for a better trade, and if no again, a chance for just some charity. -->
<event name="FUEL_TRADER_DISTRESS">
	<text load="FUEL_TRADER_DISTRESS_TEXT_LIST"/>
	<ship load="CIVILIAN_SHIP" hostile="false"/>
	<choice>
		<text>Gladly trade.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_TRADER_HIGH_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Respectfully decline.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_TRADER_PT2"/>
	</choice>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_TRADER_DISTRESS_TEXT_LIST">
	<text>A merchant ship jumps into the sector, obviously responding to your ship's distress beacon.  They hail you offering a trade for fuel.</text>
	<text>A ship arrives at the beacon.  "We noticed your distress signal.  I assume you're out of fuel?  We're a bit low ourselves but perhaps we can make a trade."</text>
	<text>A ship traveling near the beacon approaches your ship and hails you.  "Out of fuel?  This is a good opportunity for both of us...  Care to trade?"</text>
	<text>A mercenary ship arrives at the beacon.  "We have a bit of extra fuel we can give you... for a price."</text>
</textList>
<eventList name="FUEL_TRADER_HIGH_LIST">
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="2" max="4"/>
			<item type="drones" min="-2" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="2" max="5"/>
			<item type="missiles" min="-4" max="-2"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="2" max="5"/>
			<item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-25"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="FUEL_TRADER_PT2"> <!-- this list is if the player cant afford the initial trade, he'll either give up and leave or give a second cheaper offer.-->  
	<event>
		<text>They respond: "Seeing how you're in need, is this trade acceptable?"</text>
		<choice>
			<text>Accept the offer.</text>
			<event load="FUEL_TRADER_LOW_LIST"/>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">>
			<text hidden="true">Decline again.</text>
			<event load="FUEL_TRADER_PT3"/>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>"I'm not doing this for charity, you know," says their captain.  "This is the only other way I'll part with my fuel."</text>
		<choice>
			<text>Accept the offer.</text>
			<event load="FUEL_TRADER_HIGH_LIST"/>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Decline again.</text>
			<event>
				<text>Their captain disconnects from the channel and without another word their ship prepares to jumps away .</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Before they jump away, their captain says, "I'm sorry but we are unable to help in any other way."</text>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="FUEL_TRADER_LOW_LIST">
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="4" max="7"/>
			<item type="drones" min="-2" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>		
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="4" max="7"/>
			<item type="missiles" min="-2" max="-1"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="3" max="7"/>
			<item type="scrap" min="-5" max="-12"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="FUEL_TRADER_PT3">
	<event>
		<text>They take pity on you and offer you some fuel free of charge.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="1" max="6"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>They end the discussion and prepare to jump away.</text>
	</event>
</eventList>
<!--END NO_FUEL_TRADER STUFF-->	














<!-----------
		Non sector specific new events
------------>


<event name="FUEL_ON_REBEL_ATTACK">
	<text load="FUEL_ON_REBEL_ATTACK"/>
	<ship load="REBEL_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_ON_REBEL_ATTACK">
	<text>A Rebel ship hails you, "Hello citizen. We are responding to your distress call and can assist... Wait a second... You're that ship! Prepare to die!"</text>
	<text>A Rebel ship jumps nearby, "I wasn't looking forward to patrolling this boring sector but here you are, the most wanted ship in the area, just asking for me to find you. It looks like it's my lucky day!" They power up their weapons.</text>
	<text>Your distress beacon must be working because a ship just jumped nearby. You run a scan on it and activate a red alert. It's a Rebel fighter!</text>
	<text>A Rebel ship jumps in and hails you, "I knew you would slip up some time. Surrender quietly!"</text>
</event>
	

<event name="FUEL_ON_REBEL_WARNING">
	<text>A ship responding to your distress moves in. Unfortunately it turns out to be an automated Rebel scout. It immediately reverses thrust after scanning your ship.</text>
	<ship load="REBEL_AUTO_WARNING" hostile="true"/>
</event>	


<!-----------
		ENGI
		Specific no fuel events that should eventually be tied to the engi sector
------------>

<event name="FUEL_OFF_ENGI_DUBIOUS">
	<text>As you drift through space an Engi ship passes through. From listening to their com channel it sounds like they're discussing making repairs on their ship.</text>
	<ship load="FUEL_OFF_ENGI_DUBIOUS" hostile="false"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Hail them.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_OFF_ENGI_DUBIOUS_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Ignore them.</text>
		<event>
			<text>They clearly are busy because they don't notice your ship at all.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="SHIP_REPAIR">
		<text>(Hull Repair Drone) Offer to help repair their hull.</text>
		<event>
			<text>They happily accept your offer for help. Once the drone does its work they transfer over some fuel for your trouble.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="drones" min="-1" max="-1"/>
				<item type="fuel" min="4" max="6"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="FUEL_OFF_ENGI_DUBIOUS_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>The Engies respond to your signal. "Identity: Federation. I/O error: Federation = [void]." All further hails go unanswered.</text>
	</event>
	<event>	
		<text>The Engies fail to respond, but move to intercept. You detect abnormal electromagnetic signals aboard the ship - someone has reprogrammed these Engies to fight!</text>
		<ship hostile="true"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Engies respond to your signal. "Your need: fuel. This unit's need: scrap. Exchange beneficial. Exchange permitted?</text>
		<choice>
			<text>Make the trade.</text>
			<event>	
				<text>You make the exchange and the Engi leave without another word.</text>
				<item_modify>
					<item type="scrap" min="-20" max="-10"/>
					<item type="fuel" min="4" max="6"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Decline.</text>
			<event>
				<text>The Engi coolly cut communications and continue on their journey.</text>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Upon discovering your need, the Engi gladly offer some of their extra fuel reserves. It's amazing how altruistic these robotic creatures can be.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="2" max="6"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>
		

		
		

<!-----------
		ENGI
		Specific no fuel events that should eventually be tied to the engi sector
------------>
	
<event name="FUEL_ON_MANTIS_ATTACK">
	<text load="FUEL_ON_MANTIS_ATTACK"/>
	<ship load="MANTIS_FUEL" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<textList name="FUEL_ON_MANTIS_ATTACK">
	<text>A Mantis ship hails you, "Looks like we found the poor fools that need some help. Come brothers, let's 'help them!" They move in to attack.</text>
	<text>Before long a ship jumps nearby, no doubt responding to your beacon. However any relief you felt disappears as soon as you recognize the ship is of Mantis design. Prepare for a fight.</text>
	<text>You detect a Mantis ship approaching and hack into their comm channel and hear, "...hope they put up more of a fight than the last Federation ship. This has been a disappointing day so far." Looks like they're not here to help.</text>
	<text>A Mantis ship jump nearby. Sensors detect weapon locks and all hope of avoiding a fight fades away.</text>
	
	<text>A Mantis ship hails you, "Looks like we found the poor fools that need some help. Come brothers, let's 'help them!" They move in to attack.</text>
	<text>Before long a ship jumps nearby, no doubt responding to your beacon. However any relief you felt disappears as soon as you recognize the ship is of Mantis design. Prepare for a fight.</text>
	<text>You detect a Mantis ship approaching and hack into their comm channel and hear, "...hope they put up more of a fight than the last Federation ship. This has been a disappointing day so far." Looks like they're not here to help.</text>
	<text>A Mantis ship jump nearby. Sensors detect weapon locks and all hope of avoiding a fight fades away.</text>
</event>
		
		
<!-----------
		ROCKS
		Specific no fuel events that should eventually be tied to the rock sector
------------>
<event name="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_WRECK">
	<text>As you await either salvation or death, your attention is drawn to a sea of debris drifting past the starboard view port. The chunks gliding by grow bigger in size until the stern of a Rock frigate, gutted in some distant war, comes into view.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Send an away team.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Perhaps there's some viable fuel left on board; a small away team boards the vessel.</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Report!</text>
				<event load="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_WRECK_LIST"/>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Let it drift by.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The Rock don't take kindly to aliens picking through their belongings, no matter how decrepit they may seem, and you don't take risks in Rock territory. </text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>			
<eventList name="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_WRECK_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>A short time later the team returns with a stash of ammunition and scrap - but all the fuel on board is long gone.</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">missiles</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>One of the crew reports that the main computer was housed in this section and is still partially operational. They're able to download local telemetry as well the location of the ship's reserve fuel! Your map has been updated.</text>
		<reveal_map/>
		<autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The team returns home rather sooner than expected. Turns out just as they were making entry to the frigate, the ship's emergency fuel cell just happened to drift by!</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The away team reports in, but then screams are heard and the comm goes dead! When it comes back online a Rockman can be heard - he's the lone survivor from the frigate's crew, and completely mad. He demands you pay a scrap ransom in return for your crew-member's life!</text>
		<choice>
			<text>Pay.</text>
			<event>
				<text>Despite his fragile condition, the Rockman is good to his word and returns your crew-member, who is suitably grateful. Sadly, gratitude doesn't power the FTL drive.</text>  <!-- JUSTIN - TO DO - I don't like this one since you don't know who's being ransomed -->
				<item_modify >
					<item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-40"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice>
			<text>Refuse.</text>
			<event>
				<text>It's a tough call, but it's for the Federation and the liberty of all. You set off before you can change your mind.</text>
				<crewMember amount="-1"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>

<event name="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS">
	<text>A curious Rock ship comes in for a closer look at you. They refuse all hails.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Attack.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The Rock people are not renowned for their generosity. If it's fuel you need, it's fuel you must take!</text>
			<ship load="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS" hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Wait and see.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS_LIST"/>	
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>The Rock ship circles yours, running scans on your systems. You fear the worst, but the scans pause on your fuel tank. They obviously have no wish to communicate, but they transfer over a cache of fuel before flashing their lights and jumping away!</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="fuel" min="3" max="8"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Rock ship circles yours, running scans on your systems. Your worst fears are confirmed when they identify your engines and teleport a bomb straight onto it! Combat ready!</text>
		<ship load="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS" hostile="true"/>	
		<status type="limit" target="player" system="engines" amount="1"/>
	</event>
</eventList>
<ship name="FUEL_OFF_ROCK_CURIOUS" auto_blueprint="SHIPS_ROCK">
	<escape timer="80" min="30" max="30"/>
	<gotaway>
		<text>The ship jumps away without a word. You hope they didn't leave to get reinforcements.</text>
	</gotaway>
	<destroyed>
		<text>You take care to salvage as much fuel as possible from the wreck.</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">fuel</autoReward>
		<status type="clear" target="player" system="pilot" amount="100"/>
	</destroyed>
	<deadCrew>
		<text>You take care to salvage as much fuel as possible from the wreck.</text>
		<autoReward level="HIGH">fuel</autoReward>
		<status type="clear" target="player" system="engines" amount="100"/>
	</deadCrew>
</ship>






<!-----------
		SLUG
		Specific no fuel events that should eventually be tied to the slug sector
------------>

<event name="FUEL_ON_SLUG_CHUCKLE">
	<text>A poorly armed Slug ship cruises by and offers assistance. Their captain seems to be chuckling to himself, perhaps at the prices he's charging.</text>
	<ship load="JELLY" hostile="false"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Pay 15 scrap for 5 fuel.</text>
		<event load="FUEL_ON_SLUG_CHUCKLE_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Ignore the offer.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You know better than to do business with a Slugman who seems like he knows something you don't. He jumps off with another chuckle.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="slug">
		<text>(Slug Crew) Have your Slug make the purchase.</text>
		<event>
			<text>As soon as he sees your crew member the Slug stops his incessant chuckling. The exchange appears to go smoothly although you wonder what mental battles are telepathically occurring between the two Slugs.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-15"/>
				<item type="fuel" min="5" max="5"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="FUEL_ON_SLUG_CHUCKLE_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>You doubt he is trustworthy but have no choice but to make the deal. However you complete the exchange without event.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-15"/>
			<item type="fuel" min="5" max="5"/>
		</item_modify>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Continue...</text>
			<event>
				<text>Everything looks secure but suddenly a number of supplies disappear! He must have planted a portable teleporter into your cargo bay somehow. Before you can react his ship is long gone.</text>
				<item_modify steal="true">
					<item type="scrap" min="-20" max="-35"/>
					<item type="missiles" min="-4" max="-2"/>
				</item_modify>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You doubt he is trustworthy but have no choice but to make the deal. However you complete the exchange without event.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-15" max="-15"/>
			<item type="fuel" min="5" max="5"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>

<event name="FUEL_ON_SLUG_OVERPRICED">
	<text>A mobile Slugman fuel depot enters scanning range. "My prices are fair, but I ask one thing - do not insult me with negotiation!" You check out his price list.</text>
	<ship load="JELLY_OVERPRICED" hostile="false"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Buy 5 fuel for 50 scrap.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The trader looks shocked. You're struck by the sense that this is the first time anyone's ever paid him these prices.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="scrap" min="-50" max="-50"/>
				<item type="fuel" min="10" max="10"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Buy 10 fuel for 95 scrap. (BEST DEAL!)</text>
		<event>
			<text>The trader looks shocked. You're struck by the sense that this is the first time anyone's ever paid him these prices.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="scrap" min="-95" max="-95"/>
				<item type="fuel" min="10" max="10"/>
			</item_modify>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Negotiate.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You offer a more reasonable price but the Slugman is outraged! He moves in to attack!</text>
			<ship hostile="true"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

