<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. All rights reserved -->

<!--   
			SUMMARY  - 
A list of all main events to be called by lists
	does not include sub-events)
	
Structure:
	START_BEACON_ENGI
	STORE_ENGI
	NOTHING_ENGI

Items:
	ENGI_GIFT
	ENGI_FLEET_DELAY
	ENGI_MONSTER
	
Hostile:
	ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT		NEW!!!
	ENGI_REBEL_FIGHT		NEW!!!
	ENGI_PIRATE_FIGHT		NEW!!!
	
Neutral:
	ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS    (could be quest or distress - uses SAVE_ENGI_STATION)
	
Environment:
	
Boarders:

Special
--->


<!--
Idea - make an event where you're fighting to save an engi ship but theres mantis on board. - super bonus if its crewDead.

-->
	

<!--------------------------------
	ENGI EVENTLIST     ''   " " "
---------------------------------->



<eventList name="ITEMS_ENGI">
	<event load="ENGI_GIFT"/>
	<event load="ENGI_FLEET_DELAY"/>
<!--	<event load="ENGI_MONSTER"/> -->
	<event load="ENGI_SURRENDER"/>
	
	<event load="FIND_DRONE"/>
	<event load="FIND_WEAPON"/>
	<event load="REFUEL_STATION"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="HOSTILE_ENGI">
	<event load="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
	<event load="ENGI_REBEL_FIGHT"/>
	<event load="ENGI_PIRATE_FIGHT"/>
	
	<event load="PIRATE"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_CHOICE"/>
	<event load="REBEL"/>
	<event load="SQUAT_WARNING"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_ASTEROID"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_SUN"/>
	<event load="PIRATE_NO_ESCAPE"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="NEUTRAL_ENGI">
	<!--<event load="ENGI_UNLOCK_1"/> -->
	<event load="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS"/>
	<event load="MANTIS_FIGHT_CHOICE"/>
	<event load="MANTIS_CIVILIAN"/>
	
	<event load="PIRATE_BRIBER"/>
	<event load="ASTEROID_EXPLORE"/>
	<event load="BROKEN_REBEL_DRONE"/>
	<event load="AUTO_DEFENSE_ITEM"/> 
	
	<event load="ALISON_MANTIS_CREW"/> <!-- new alison written event -->
	
	<event load="ZOLTAN_CREW_STUDY"/>
	
	<event load="ASTEROID_DERELICT_SHIP"/> <!-- CRYSTAL UNLOCK-->
</eventList>

<eventList name="DISTRESS_BEACON_ENGI">
	<event load="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR"/>
	
	<event load="CIVILIAN_ASTEROIDS_BEACON"/>  
	<event load="FRIENDLY_BEACON"/>
	<event load="TRAP_BEACON"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_TRAPPED_MINER"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_INFESTATION"/>
	<event load="DISTRESS_SATELLITE_DEFENSE"/>
</eventList>

<eventList name="QUESTS_ENGI">
	<event load="QUEST_ESCORT"/>
	<event load="MERCHANT_REQUEST"/>
	<event load="FEDERATION_PLANET_SIGNAL"/>
	<event load="MERCENARY_WORK_START"/>
</eventList>






<!-----------
		STRUCTURE!!!
	Others events necessary for strucrtural stuff
------------>

<event name="START_BEACON_ENGI">
	<text load="START_BEACON_ENGI"/>
</event>
<textList name="START_BEACON_ENGI">
	<text>You have arrived in Engi space. The Mantis have been threatening the Engi core worlds, but you should be able to stock up for your journey.</text>
	<text>You have arrived in Engi space. The fall of the Federation has brought tough times for these robotic lifeforms, but they're usually willing to help.</text>
</textList>

<event name="STORE_ENGI">
	<text load="STORE_ENGI"/>
	<store/>
</event>
<textList name="STORE_ENGI">
	<text>The Engi can do remarkable things with just a pile of scrap. The Engi hive at this beacon are selling equipment for just that.</text>
	<text>A message arrives: "Your scrap, ours. Our weapons for you." You're about to raise the shields when you realise it's just an Engi trader looking for a trade.</text>
	<text>An Engi ship hails: "Engine upgrade necessary for travel home. Sale of equipment necessary for engine upgrade."</text>
</textList>

<event name="NOTHING_ENGI">
	<text load="NOTHING_ENGI"/>
</event>
<textList name="NOTHING_ENGI">
	<text>The complex arrangements of ship hulls and FTL drive capacitors floating abandoned in space suggest the Engi were here not too long ago; but no longer.</text>
	<text>You arrive at a green planet with great plains and rolling waterfalls. It would be of little interest to the Engi nearby.</text>  <!-- JUSTIN TO DO-  MAKE GREEN PLANET-->
	<text>You have arrived near an Engi construction yard.  Most Engi's maintain their bi-pedal appearance out of habit but here you see a number of Engi hives working together to create massive organic machines adept at building ships.  Truly a sight to behold.</text>
	<text>Even though each "individual" Engi is made up of trillions of nano-machines, their culture still revolves around traditional social interactions.  A nearby station seems to be constructed for entertainment of passing Engi travellers.</text>
	<text>You see a number of Engi space stations and fleets nearby.  Despite looking like piles of junk loosely tied together they are actually a model of efficiency.  They just lack a certain aesthetic emphasis in their constructions.</text>
	<text>This system appears quite peaceful.  You're not sure how long it'll last between the combined threats of the Rebels and Mantis.</text>
	<text>There are a number of merchant ships passing through the area despite the threat of Mantis invasion.  No doubt interested in buying the efficient technology of the Engi.</text>
	<text>You see a small Rebel carrier in the distance.  You lay low and try to blend in with the other traffic.  However it's surprising to see a Rebel military ship alone deep in Engi space.</text>
	<text>The Engi seem to have avoided this particular node, along with every other life-form. You keep your eyes peeled for reasons why, but spin up the FTL without event.</text>
	<text>A cluster of Engi satellites in orbit of a nearby planet are the only clue the mechanical species was ever here.   You have other places to be.</text>
</textList>








<!-----------
		ITEMS!!!
	Events that give items
------------>

<event name="ENGI_GIFT">
	<text load="ENGI_GIFT"/>
	<autoReward level="RANDOM">standard</autoReward>
</event>
<textList name="ENGI_GIFT">
	<text>An Engi vessel hails you. "Identity: Federation? Outlier probability. Implies... revival. Implies... hope.  Assistance suggested."  They offer some supplies.</text>
	<text>You cross paths with an Engi cargo vessel hurrying home before the Mantis fleets attempt to take over this sector. They're happy to offload some of their cargo to get home faster.</text>
	<text>You make contact with an isolated Engi science station who are staying put despite the likelihood of Mantis invasion. They suggest you trial some experimental technology.</text>
	<text>This was the site of a recent battle. Either a show of Mantis force, or the Engi here weren't disposed to go peacefully. You pick through the pieces.</text>
</textList>

<event name="ENGI_FLEET_DELAY" unique="true">
	<text>You notice an Engi colony hiding on the other side of a nearby moon. It turns out they're excavating an equipment cache from the Federation-Mantis War, and they suggest it might be used to lure the pursuing rebel fleet.</text>
	<choice>
		<text>Booby trap the cache.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You transfer down some missile warheads and the Engi rig them to blow before setting a distress signal to attract the fleet's attention.</text>
			<item_modify>
				<item type="missiles" min="-2" max="-2"/>
			</item_modify>
			<modifyPursuit amount="-2"/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Secure the cache.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You have the Engi complete their excavations and bring the supplies on-board.</text>
			<autoReward level="MED">drone</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>

<event name="ENGI_MONSTER" unique="true">  <!-- TO DO - Need black image!!!!!! JUSTIN!!!! -->
	<img back="BG_DARK" planet="NONE"/>
	<text>As you jump in you're hailed urgently by an Engi science vessel in the distance. "We propose that you do not see the creature." There's nothing on the scanner, which is when you realise you can't see the creature because you're inside it!</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Jump away ASAP.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="3">
		<text>(Improved Sensors) Scan the monstrosity.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You detect a faint, arrhythmic sub-wave pattern. Could the creature be communicating? You forward your observations to the Engi vessel and they thank you in turn.</text>
			<autoReward level="LOW">augment</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="ADV_SCANNERS">
		<text>(Long-Ranged Scanners) Scan the monstrosity.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You detect a faint, arrhythmic sub-wave pattern. Could the creature be communicating? You forward your observations to the Engi vessel and they thank you in turn.</text>
			<autoReward level="LOW">augment</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>




<event name="ENGI_SURRENDER" unique="true">
	<text>An Engi ship in the vicinity, seeing you jump in armed to the teeth, immediately broadcasts its surrender: "Subject goal: wealth. Engi motivation: survival. Transfer of goods acceptable?"</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Explain that you're friendly.</text>
		<event load="ENGI_SURRENDER_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Accept their offer of surrender.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The Engi obediently transfer over the goods and get on their way. Money for nothing.</text>
			<autoReward level="RANDOM">standard</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="ENGI_SURRENDER_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>The Engi seem relieved, and eager to get underway. They set off without saying goodbye.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Engi are satisfied with your explanation. "Beneficial. Subject goal: long, long journey. Remains compatible with transfer of goods from Engi." They send over the gear willingly, and you feel better for it.</text>
		<autoReward level="RANDOM">standard</autoReward>
	</event>
</eventList>






<!-----------
		HOSTILE!!!
	Events that call up a fight for sure
------------>

<event name="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT">
	<text load="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT"/>
	<ship load="MANTIS_FIGHT" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<textList name="ENGI_MANTIS_FIGHT">
	<text>A mixed radar signal turns out to be a Mantis attack ship scavenging the remains of an Engi carrier. They turn and fight.</text>
	<text>You come across a Mantis raider taking pot shots at a defenceless Engi supply station. Discovering its weapons aren't much of a match for the station's armour, it turns on your ship.   Battlestations!</text>
	<text>The area looks clear, and you prepare to jump off, but a Mantis scout jumps in behind you! They're as surprised as you are, but their weapons are already online.</text>
	<text>You find a Mantis ship harrying a small squad of Engi. They make it to the node and jump off, leaving you toe to toe with their pursuer!</text>
</textList>

<event name="ENGI_REBEL_FIGHT">
	<text>The rebel fighter here would seem to suggest elements of the rebel fleet are already making incursions on Engi space. You move to engage.</text>
	<ship load="REBEL" hostile="true"/>
</event>

<event name="ENGI_PIRATE_FIGHT">
	<text>There must have been rich pickings for pirates around here up until war broke out. The pirate you encounter here looks worn down, but hungry. You'll have to fight!</text>
	<ship load="PIRATE" hostile="true"/>
</event>




<!-----------
		NEUTRAL!!!
	Events that could have a fight
------------>

<event name="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS" unique="false">
	<text>You receive a distress call from a nearby Engi ship.  "Assistance requested.  Danger present.  Imminent destruction."</text>
	<choice>
		<text>Respond to the call and move in to assist.</text>
		<event load="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Keep your distance.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="ENGI_STATION_DISTRESS_LIST">
	<event>
		<text>You receive another message from the ship, this time with a Mantis at the com-log.  "Foolish meatsacks," he yells.  Sensors indicate the ship is moving in to attack and boarders teleport from the station.</text>
		<ship load="ENGI_MANTIS_CONTROLLED" hostile="true"/>
		<boarders min="1" max="2" class="mantis"/>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>You approach to find a Mantis ship assaulting a small Engi space station.  You prepare for a fight!</text>
		<ship load="MANTIS_ENGI_STATION" hostile="true"/>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="SAVE_ENGI_STATION">
	<event>
		<text>The Engi station is stripped bare and there are signs of a fierce battle.  The Mantis must have left the distress call active to lure other ships into a trap.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The station was in the process of being evacuated.  A number of civilian Engies offer their gratitude as they finalize their preparations to leave.  They offer some fuel as a reward.</text>
		<autoReward level="MED">fuel_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The station hails you, "Gratitude.  Expected probability of defeat without assistance... 86.2 percent.  Request suitable reward."</text>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Request fuel.</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Request granted.  Fuel transferring."</text>
				<autoReward level="HIGH">fuel</autoReward>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Request weapon.</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Request granted.  Weapon transferring."</text>
				<autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Request drone.</text>
			<event>
				<text>"Request granted.  Drone schematic transferring."</text>
				<autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
			</event>
		</choice>
		<choice req="engi" hidden="true">
			<text>(Engi Crew) Threat unresolved.  Current mission imperative: Protocol 52.34.</text>
			<event>
				<text>They respond, "Understood.  Re-establishment of Federation highest import.  Transmitting hidden base coordinates.  Repairing hull and attaching ship to ship ordnance."</text>
				<autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
				<quest event="HIDDEN_FEDERATION_BASE_LIST"/>
				<damage amount="-10"/>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>They thank you for the assistance and when you tell them of your mission, one of the Engies ask if he can assist your crew.  You welcome him aboard.</text>
		<crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>
		<autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
	</event>
</eventList>



<!-----------
		DISTRESS!!!
	Events that havea distress beacon  
------------>

<event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL" unique="true">
	<text>The distress signal originates at a small Engi ship under attack by a rebel fighter - but when they see Federation markings they turn to attack!</text> 
	<distressBeacon/>
	<ship load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_RESULT">
	<text>The Engi vessel turns out to be very poorly equipped - barely a runabout, really. They're trying to outrun the rebels, and need all the help they can get.</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Give them 25 scrap.</text>
		<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_LIST1"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Give them 40 scrap, 2 missiles and 2 fuel.</text>
		<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_LIST2"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Give them nothing.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Engies can't feel fear, so they bear you no ill will when you explain you're unwilling to help. They set off on their journey and you do the same.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_LIST1">
	<event>
		<text>The words they use are "Need = fulfilled", but you take it for gratitude. They take the next jump in their long journey home.</text>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Engies are grateful. They don't have any supplies or weapons to spare, but they do send over a self-teleporting med-bot disperser they hope they won't need.</text>
		<weapon name="BOMB_HEAL"/>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Engies are grateful. They don't have much by way of supplies but they do offer a drone schematic for your use.</text>
		<drone name="RANDOM"/>
		<item_modify>
			<item type="scrap" min="-25" max="-25"/>
		</item_modify>
	</event>
</eventList>
<event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REBEL_LIST2">
	<text>They wouldn't get more than a few jumps with that load-out. You provide them with all the munitions and supplies they should need for the journey home. "Generosity magnitude unpredicted. Well-being syntax error [value too high]. Accept this token."</text>
	<item_modify>
		<item type="scrap" min="-40" max="-40"/>
		<item type="fuel" min="-2" max="-2"/>
		<item type="missiles" min="-2" max ="-2"/>
	</item_modify>
	<augment name="NANO_MEDBAY"/>
</event>
		
		
		
<event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR" unique="true">
	<text>You arrive at a smoldering Engi research station, its distress call unanswered - attacked by pirates or Mantis most likely. There may be someone left alive, or else something of value left on board.</text>
	<distressBeacon/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Board the station.</text>
		<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_LIST1"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Ignore it.</text>
		<event>
			<text>The place looks in bad state, probably nothing of use there. Time to move on.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="sensors" lvl="2">
		<text>(Improved Sensors) Run another scan.</text>
		<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_SCAN"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="ADV_SCANNERS">
		<text>(Long Ranged Scanners) Run another scan.</text>
		<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_SCAN"/>
	</choice>
</choice>
<eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_LIST1">
	<event>
		<text>You send an away team to investigate, but there's nothing save for the acidic stench of burnt Engi parts. This place is dead.</text>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Your away team reports a wounded Engi and a functioning drone schematic. Then someone yells. The station reactor is overloading and they're running out of time!</event>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Save the Engi!</text>
			<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_ENGI"/>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">	
			<text>Save the drone schematic.</text>
			<event load="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_DRONE"/>
		</choice>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Save yourselves!</text>
			<event>
				<text>It's a tough order, but your crew's lives are the priority. They drop everything and return to ship unharmed. You put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
				<autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_ENGI">
	<event>
		<text>One of your crew valiantly grabs the Engi and throws it into the airlock right before the reactor blows and the automatic blast doors slam shut. You have no choice but to mourn their sacrifice and move on.</text>
		<crewMember amount="-1"/>
		<choice hidden="true">
			<text>Continue...</text>
			<event>
				<text>The Engi who was saved offers to join your crew.</text>
				<crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>  
				<autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
			</event>
		</choice>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>Your crew return safely to the airlock with the injured Engi and you put some distance on the station before it blows. The Engi, impressed by your crew, volunteers to join you.</text>
		<crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>  
		<autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
	</event>
</eventList>
<eventList name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_DRONE">
	<event>
		<text> Your away team heads home with the goods, but as they transfer back to the ship a small explosion blows the airlock and one of the crew is sucked out into space!</text>
		<crewMember amount="-1"/>
		<autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
	</event>
	<event>
		<text>The Engi don't feel things the same way other species do. They'd want the tech to be saved. Your crew return safely to the airlock with the drone control and you put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
		<autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
	</event>
</eventList>
<event name="DISTRESS_ENGI_REACTOR_SCAN">
	<text>Scans reveal the station's reactor is overloading! Not only that, but an injured Engi and a functioning drone schematic are still on board! There's not time for both...</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Save the Engi!</text>
		<event>
			<text>Your away team heads straight for the Engi and returns with time to spare. You put some distance on the station before it blows and the Engi is so impressed by your crew that they volunteer to join you!</text>
			<crewMember amount="1" class="engi"/>  
			<autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Save the Drone Schematic!</text>
		<event>
			<text>The Engi don't feel things the same way other species do. They'd want the tech to be saved. Your away team heads straight for the goods and returns with time to spare. You put some distance on the station before it blows.</text>
			<autoReward level="LOW">drone</autoReward>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>


<!-----------
		SPECIAL!!!
	Unique events
------------>

<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_1" unique="true">
	<text>You arrive near a small fleet of civilian Engi ships.  A simple decryption and translation of their comm frequency tells you that they are having a frantic discussion about something obviously troubling them.</text> 
	<choice>
		<text>Message them and ask if you can help.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Slightly shocked at your question, their leader quickly responds, "Declined offer with apologetic gratitude.   Topic of discussion private matter, no concern of Federation."</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Ignore it and move on.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You can't help but wonder what they were discussing as you prepare to jump.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice req="engi" hidden="true">
		<text>(Engi Crew) Have your Engi crew member contact them.</text>
		<event>
			<text>Your crew member syncs with the comm unit to communicate with them directly.  You offer your help and a summary of the ship's mission.  They respond, "Our goals have analogous elements.  However, not all available for disclosure, discretion necessary."</text>
			<choice>
				<text>Offer your help.</text>
				<event>
					<text>"Secret technologies stolen by Mantis.  Implicit connection to Rebels.  Implicit.  Tracked Mantis to hidden Rebel base, uploading coordinates."</text>
					<quest event="ENGI_UNLOCK_2REAL"/>
					<choice>
						<text>Continue...</text>
						<event>
							<quest event="ENGI_UNLOCK_2FAKE"/>
							<text>"However, tracked second ship to different base.  Would calculate probability but data insufficient.  Cannot risk obvious Rebel-Engi conflict.  Also, need time to acquire military ships.  Assist in finding technology?"</text>
							<choice>
								<text>Agree.</text>
								<event/>
							</choice>
						</event>
					</choice>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_2FAKE">
	<text>You arrive at one of the Rebel bases that the Engies told you about.  It appears abandoned except for one scout ship.  Perhaps you could extract information from them.</text>
	<ship load="REBEL_ENGI_UNLOCK_2FAKE" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_2FAKE_SURRENDER">
	<text>"Stop!  I don't want to die here."</text>
	<choice>
		<text>Demand information on the stolen technology.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Ah, so that's what you're after.  Too bad, you followed the wrong ship.  The envoy that passed through here was a fake, to trick fools like you.  Now let us go!"</text>
			<choice>
				<text>Let them go.</text>
				<event>
					<ship hostile="false"/>
				</event>
			</choice>
			<choice>
				<text>Ignore him and attack.</text>
				<event>
					<text>"No, wait..."  You cut the transmission and continue the assault.</text>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_2REAL">
	<text>You arrive at one of the Rebel bases that the Engies told you about.  It appears abandoned except for one scout ship.  Perhaps you could extract information from them."</text>
	<ship load="REBEL_ENGI_UNLOCK_2REAL" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_2REAL_SURRENDER">
	<text>"Stop!  This isn't worth dying for..."</text>
	<choice>
		<text>Demand information on the stolen technology.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Of course, that's why you're here.  Yes, they passed by here but I had nothing to do with it, I don't know what they were carrying.  I'll transmit coordinates.  Now just let us go..."</text>
			<quest event="ENGI_UNLOCK_3"/>
			<choice>
				<text>Let them go.</text>
				<event>
					<text>You prepare an FTL message containing the coordinates to send to the Engies and get ready to jump.</text>
					<ship hostile="false"/>
				</event>
			</choice><!--   REMOVED THIS TO PREVENT DOUBLE QUESTS
			<choice>
				<text>Ignore him and attack.</text>
				<event>
					<text>"But we..."  You cut the transmission and prepare an FTL message containing the coordinates to send to the Engies.  You then focus on the battle.</text>
				</event>
			</choice>-->
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_3">
	<text>You have finally caught up with the ships you've been hunting.  A hangar-sized cargo ship is being escorted by a number of Mantis ships.  As you reconsider the assault, a squadron of Engi ships with pirate emblems jump in and assist you.  You prepare to fight the Mantis but scans indicate they are manned by Rebels!</text>
	<ship load="MANTIS_ENGI_UNLOCK_3" hostile="true"/>
</event>
<event name="ENGI_UNLOCK_4">
	<text>The Engi emerge victorious from their battles with only minor losses.  They message you, "Project X-ME56 commissioned by Federation military research division.  Advanced stealth cruiser.  Project finished during rebellion.  Unable to reconnect with Federation military command."</text>
	<choice>
		<text>Ask about the Mantis ships.</text>
		<event>
			<text>"Likely ploy by Rebels to avoid breaking non-aggression pact with Engi.  97.56 percent likely.  Your mission to assist last Federation fleet, correct?  Coordinates?"</text>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Transmit coordinates of Federation command.</text>
				<event>
					<text>"Satisfactory.  Delivery of tech will assist in Federation cause.  Gratitude alone insufficient.  Commencing ship repair and compensation."  Their crews deliver a weapon for installation but you're more pleased to hear that the Federation will have an improved arsenal.</text>
					<damage amount="-20"/>
					<autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
					<unlockShip id="1">The Engi secret tech has been delivered to the hangar.  The stealth ship has been unlocked!</unlockShip>
				</event>
			</choice>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>