<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. All rights reserved -->

<!-- SYSTEM TOOLTIPS FOR THE BOTTOM -->
<oxygen>Oxygen: Replenishes the ship's oxygen supply.</oxygen>
<doors>Doors: Allows for remote opening/closing of doors.</doors>
<shields>Shields: Sustains damage-reducing shields. Manning increases shield recharge speed.</shields>
<pilot>Piloting: Requires a crew member to evade in combat or jump.</pilot>
<engines>Engines: Charges the FTL drive and powers evasion. Manning increases dodge chance.</engines>
<sensors>Sensors: Enables view of all rooms and info for enemy ships.</sensors>
<medbay>Medbay: Heals crewmembers inside the Medbay</medbay>
<weapons>Weapons: Click on a weapon to charge and fire. Manning reduces charge time.</weapons>
<drones>Drones: Automated robots for attack and defense.</drones>
<teleporter>Teleporter: Send crewmembers in the teleporter room to board enemy ships.</teleporter>
<cloaking>Cloaking: Temporarily hide from enemies.</cloaking>
<artillery>Artillery: Beam that automatically fires a 1 damage beam that pierces all shields.</artillery>
<powerTotal>Reactor: Unused reactor energy available to power your systems.</powerTotal>

<!-- Ship status tooltips -->
<hull>Current hull integrity. If it drops to zero, the ship is destroyed.</hull>
<droneCount>Number of Drone Parts.  Using a Drone consumes one Drone Part.</droneCount>
<fuelCount>Amount of fuel. Each jump consumes one fuel.</fuelCount>
<missileCount>Number of missiles.  Some weapons consume one Missile when fired.</missileCount>
<scrapCount>Current scrap total</scrapCount>
<FTLButton>Opens star map to choose jump location.</FTLButton>
<shieldDisplay>Current shield status.</shieldDisplay>
<evadeDisplay>Percent chance to dodge incoming fire.</evadeDisplay>
<oxygenDisplay>Ship's current oxygen.</oxygenDisplay>
<energyShieldDisplay>Zoltan Energy Shield: Will completely block incoming damage of any weapon type.</energyShieldDIsplay>

<!-- Other -->
<autofire>Toggle to active/deactive weapons automatically firing.</autoFire>

<asteroids>You're in an asteroid field. Periodically asteroids will strike your ship.</asteroids>
<sun>You're too close to a star. Solar flares will light the ship on fire.  Shields will reduce the effect.</sun>
<nebula>You're inside of a nebula. Your sensors will not function, but the rebel fleet will advance more slowly towards you.</nebula>
<storm>This section of the nebula is experiencing a plasma storm. Your main reactor can only function at half capacity.</storm>