<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- TO DO - EVENTS TO ADD TO THINGS 








--->
<!-- 
----
Events For Testing
----
--->
<event name="FUEL_ESCAPE_PULSAR">
	<text>Taking advantage of the last of your fuel reserves, you were able to navigate to a safe distance from the pulsar.</text>
</event>

<event name="PULSAR">
	<text>Oh no! A pulsar!</text>
	<ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
	<environment type="pulsar"/>
</event>

<event name="PDS_TEST">
	<text>Oh no! This planet is friendly to the Rebels and is shooting at us!</text>
	<environment type="PDS" target="all"/>
	<ship load="REBEL_AUTO" hostile="true"/>
</event>

<event name="FUEL_ESCAPE_PDS">
	<text>Using your impulse engines, you were able to pull to a safe distance from the hostile planet.</text>
</event>

<event name="FUEL_ESCAPE_FLEET">
	<text>Your pilot deftly avoids the artillery fire from the surrounding fleet while you try to sort out exactly what your plan is....</text>
</event>

<event name="NEWSHIP1">
	<text>whatever</text>
	<ship load="NEWSHIP1" hostile="true"/>
</event>
	
<event name="NEWSHIP2">
	<text>whatever</text>
	<ship load="NEWSHIP2" hostile="true"/>
</event>
	
<ship name="NEWSHIP1" auto_blueprint="ANAEROBIC_SCOUT">
	<destroyed>
		<text>Yay</text>
	</destroyed>
	<deadCrew>
		<text>Yay</text>
	</deadCrew>
</ship>

<ship name="NEWSHIP2" auto_blueprint="ANAEROBIC_BOMBER">
	<destroyed>
		<text>Yay</text>
	</destroyed>
	<deadCrew>
		<text>Yay</text>
	</deadCrew>
	<surrender  chance="0.5" min="3" max="4" load="PIRATE_SURRENDER"/>
</ship>






<!-- 
----
New Item Events
----
--->
<event name="STORE_REBELSIDE" unique="true">
	<text>You come across a large trade station. However, as soon as you approach a warning goes out to all ships in the region: "Do not associate with the Federation sympathizer. All who oppose the Rebels will be punished."</text>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Search among the stores to see if someone will sell to you.</text>
		<event load="STORE_REBELSIDE_SEARCH"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Leave.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You decide it's better to not push your luck and move on.</text>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="1" max_group="0">
		<text>(Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
			<store/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="2" max_group="0">
		<text>(Improved Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. In addition he apologizes by offering complimentary supplies. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
			<autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
			<store/>
		</event>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="mind" lvl="3" max_group="0">
		<text>(Advanced Mind Control) Alter the announcer's opinions.</text>
		<event>
			<text>You locate the source of the announcement and 'convince' the speaker to rescind his previous statement. In addition he apologizes by offering considerable complimentary supplies. Hopefully you will have enough time to shop before he can figure out what just happened.</text>
			<autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
			<store/>
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>
